In the final exercise for this module, we're gonna start with
在本单元最后的这个练习里 我们会从上一个练习中
the webpage that we completed at the end of the previous exercise.
我们完成的那个网页着手
And add a few more features first.
并为其加进一些功能
We will build in a navigation structure for our website.
我们将会为我们的网站 搭建一个导航架构
We will do that by including a navigation bar into our webpage and then
为此 我们会在我们的各个网页中 加进一个导航栏
add in the links to other webpages that are going to form part of our website.
然后 我们要在这个导航栏中 放进一些能导航到其它网页的链接
Now the remaining pages will be added as we go through other modules
对于后续单元中实现的网页
of this course.
预测性分析
We will put the navigation structure into place at this moment.
不过架构的搭建将在这个练习中完成
The second item that we are going to look at in this exercise is the use of
我们要做的第二件事情
Icon font in designing our web pages.
是尝试使用图标字体 来设计我们的网页
In particular, we'll look at Font Awesome and
特别地 我们将会学习如何使用 Font Awesome 的一些图标
the built in glyphicons that come with Bootstrap and
以及 Bootstrap 自带的 glyphicons
also we'll look at adding Bootstrap social buttons, in order to create
我们还会用到 Bootstrap social buttons 【Bootstrap 社交按钮】
buttons to various social websites on our webpage.
它们是长得像一些 社交网站的 logo 的按钮
As I mentioned in the body of a ratio replace just before the header I'm
正如我之前所说的 我们要在 这坨 HTML 代码中的 body 标签下
going to paste the code to create the navbar.
实现我们的导航栏
So as you can see I have already pasted the code for the navbar I am using the nav
你可以看到我已经在这里 贴好了相应的代码
element from HTML5 And I have styled it with the navbar,
你可以看到我用了 HTML5 中的 nav 标签 来实现这个导航栏 同时我对其设置了
navbar-inverse and navbar-static-top classes.
class="navbar navbar-inverse navbar-static-top" 其中 navbar 声明了其导航栏的身份
What this means is that this navbar will appear at the top of the page.
navbar-inverse 用于定制其样式 navbar-static-top 则意味着
Taking a look at the web page, you can see that the navbar is displayed
该导航栏将在页面顶部显示 且当我上下滚动页面时
at the top of the page and will scroll as I scroll the page.
该导航栏会随页面滚动
In addition, you notice that that Home link
特别的 你可以看到导航栏中
on the navbar is highlighted with a darker background.
Home 链接被高亮显示了
Now, I am using the active class in order to highlight the.
这是因为我对其设置了 active 这个类
Going back to our navbar code, you notice that inside my navbar I have a container.
回到代码部分 你会发现我在 nav 标签下面放了一个设置了
And within the container I am using a unsorted list.
class="container" 的 div 然后在这个 div 里面 我放了一个 ul 标签
And I am styling it with the class nav navbar-nav.
我对其设置了 class="nav navbar-nav"
So this is where the links that appear on our navbar are included.
然后这个 ul 里面装着的 就是我们导航栏中的内容了
The home link, in particular, I have styled using the active class.
特别的 你可以看到我对 Home 那一项 设置了 class="active"
And hence, it has been highlighted on the screen.
这也是它被高亮的原因
Going back to our web page, let's see how the navbar behaves as we
回到我们的网页 让我们看看 我们现在的导航栏的表现如何
resize that browser window.
当我们改变我们的窗口大小时
So you can see that the navbar continues to be displayed at the top, but
你可以看到导航栏一直都 留在页面的顶部
when we hit the extra small screen size,
不过当我们的窗口太小的时候
do you notice that the navbar is now being displayed vertically?
你会发现我们的导航栏竖起来了
Now this is obviously going to look look ugly on small screens.
这看上去很丑
How do we turn this navbar into a responsive navbar?
所以我们要把我们的导航栏 设计成响应式的
Meaning that when you are displaying it on extra small screens,
这意味着当显示窗口太小的时候
I want this content of the navbar to be hidden and
该导航栏能够自动隐藏起来
only shown when I explicitly ask for it to be shown.
并允许用户通过某些途径 来控制其显示与否
Returning to our navbar,
回到代码部分
I have pasted in additional code in order to make it responsive.
我已经贴好了相应的代码
We have seen this code already in the lecture earlier.
事实上在之前的课中 我们已经见过这段代码了
So this code is exactly similar to what I have shown you
事实上这段代码和之前我们
earlier when we discussed about bootstraps navbar.
讨论 Bootstrap 导航栏时 展现的代码长得很像
So this makes the navbar responsive.
这些代码将会把我们的导航栏 变成响应式的导航栏
So after this change, let's go and have a look at our web page and
做完这些后 让我们回去看看 我们的网页变咋样了吧
see how it responds when the browser window is shut.
我们要重点看看我们导航栏的表现
Returning to the web page, we can now see that the navbar has the additional
首先你可以看到我们的导航栏中
brand shown within the navbar.
多出了这么一个商标
In addition, as I shrink the webpage, you notice that
然后当我缩小窗口大小时
when the page reaches the extra small size, the links
特别的 当其达到了 extra small 这个大小时
in the navbar are now hidden, and instead, to be replaced by this button here.
你可以看到我们导航栏的 主体部分都被隐藏起来了
When I click on the button, the items in the navbar are displayed,
然后在右边这里多出了一个按钮 事实上这个按钮就是控制导航栏的显示与否的
so I can click and hide by toggling, using this button.
所以我可以通过点击这个按钮 来显示或隐藏导航栏
As a next step, I'm going to introduce a drop down into the navbar.
下一步我们要做的 是在我们的 导航栏中实现一个下拉菜单
I'm going to take the Menu link in the navbar,
我们将在导航栏中的 Menu 链接处 实现一个下拉菜单
and then when I click on the Menu link, it'll display a list of
从而当我们点击这个 Menu 链接时
items or categories of items in the menu, so
它会显示出一些类别
that their visitor can be directly taken to any one of those categories,
从而访问者能通过它们直接访问 这些类别所对应的菜式信息的网页
like appetizers, main courses, desserts, and so on.
比如说 开胃菜 主菜 甜品 之类的
So, let's go ahead and make the change the code,
那么接下来让我们去看看
and then review it, to introduce the drop-down Into our navbar.
实现这些功能的代码吧
I have replaced the menu link that we had in the unsorted list
你可以看到我对 Menu 这一项 做了一些更改
by this list item, whose class is dropdown.
我对其本身设置了 class="dropdown" 并在其中加进了一个 ul 标签
So inside this list item, we have the contents of the dropdown enclosed here.
对这个 ul 标签 我设置了 class="dropsown-toggle"
Again inside another unsorted list which is.
然后这个 ul 标签中装的 就是我们下拉菜单中的内容了
Styled with the class dropdown-menu.
你可以看到每一项链接都是一个 li 标签 且 li 标签中还有一个 a 标签
So, this list will be displayed when I click on the menu item.
而这个 a 标签的 href 属性的值 就是该链接将会导航到的地方
Let's go visit the web page one more time.
让我们回到我们的网页
Taking a look at the web page now, you'll see that the Menu
你可以看到这个 Menu 链接
item has now been replaced with a Menu drop-down.
已经变成了一个下拉菜单
You'll see the small inverted triangle there, indicating the caret.
你可以看到它旁边有一个小倒三角
Now, when I click on the item,
当我点击这个链接时
you can see the items on the drop-down being displayed here.
你可以看到一列东西弹了出来
The next modification that I'm going to introduce is
我们接下来要做的是
to turn the navbar from a navbar static top to a navbar fixed top.
把这个导航栏从 navbar-static-top 变成 navbar-fixed-top
So I'm gonna go in and change the class from navbar-static-top
为此 直接更改导航栏的
to navbar-fixed-top in the navigation code.
class 属性就行了
Now in addition I'm going to paste in some
特别的 我还将在 mystyle.css 文件中
additional CSS classes into mystyle.css file.
加进了一些新的 CSS 类
So let me paste that and then we'll review it quickly.
我现在就去把代码贴好
The additional code that I pasted into the mystyle.css
你可以看到 mystyle.css 这里 多了一些代码
file allows me to style the navbar in a bit more detail.
这些代码比较细致地定制了 我们刚刚做的那个导航栏
In particular, I am giving the body a padding of 50 pixels, because now,
特别的 我对 body 设置了一个 50 像素的 padding
since the navbar is fixed at the top of the page, the navbar is going to
这是因为导航栏将总会
cover the top 50 pixels of the browser window.
占据页面顶部 50 像素的空间
If our body of our page scrolls, then the top 50
为了防止页面滚动时 页面顶部的 50 像素的内容被导航栏挡住
pixels are gonna be hidden underneath the navbar.
我对 body 做了这样的设置
So, to avoid that, I'm giving a upper margin of 50 pixels,
也就是设置 padding: 50px 0 0 0
so that the body is displayed below the navbar.
从而页面主体内容将会总是在 导航栏的下方显示
And will still be able to scroll without getting hidden by the navbar on top.
而不会被总是在顶部的导航栏遮住
I have also customized the navbar color itself.
我还定制了导航栏的颜色
I have redefined navbar-inverse to have a background color.
比如 我把 navbar-inverse 的 背景颜色改成了
This reaches a darker shade of indigo.
#1A237E 这个比靛蓝色 深一点的颜色
In, addition I have customized a few more of the navbar classes.
我还定制了导航栏其它的一些属性
So I have made sure that,
比如我把
The navbar, if I am using the active class,
高亮链接的背景色
that background color is going to be even darker shade of indigo.
调成了比靛蓝色更深一点的颜色
And also, the color for the text is going to be white.
同时我把字体颜色调成了白色
So, with this change, whenever I declare any one of the list
由于我是直接对 CSS 进行更改
items in the navbar to be a active link,
所以这些设置将是全局性的
then that will be colored even darker than the navbar's color.
无论我在哪里使用这些标签 这些设置都会生效
In addition, also for the drop down menu, you saw that
我还对下拉菜单做了定制
drop down was being displayed with Pale background with darker lettering.
你可以看到我把它的背景色调成了浅色 并把其字体调成了深色
I have changed that to follow the same color as the navbar itself.
当然了 具体颜色还是和 导航栏的色调是一致的
So after these changes, let's go and take a quick look at the.
做完这些后 让我们看看 我们的网页现在长啥样吧
Now, going to the web page,
来到网页这里
you can now notice that my navbar has acquired a dark indigo color.
你可以看到导航栏的背景色 变成了深靛蓝色
This is to contrast this with the lighter indigo colors after.
这是为了和超大屏幕的 浅靛蓝色区分开来
In addition you see that the active link is even more darker than
特别的 你可以看到设置了 active 的链接 的背景色是更深一点的靛蓝色
the dark indigo that I am using for the navbar.
比导航栏用的深靛蓝色还深
So that the highlighted link is more clearly visible.
这样一来 高亮的链接就显得很突出
The Menu items, when I click on that you see that
对于 Menu 链接 当我点击它后
the background color of the drop down has been changed, and
你可以看到下拉菜单的背景色 变成了和导航栏一样的颜色
the items themselves are now displayed in light color.
然后其中的每一项则是用 浅色来显示的
And as I scroll through the items, the selected item is clearly identified.
同时 你可以看到我鼠标悬停处的选项 会被高亮表现出来
Now, when you scroll this, Web page,
而如果你滚动页面主体部分的话
you notice that the scrolling,
你会发现导航栏不随页面滚动而滚动 而是一直留在页面顶部
none of the part of the web page is hidden under the navbar.
同时页面的主体内容 不会被顶部的导航栏遮挡
Our last modification to the webpage
我们最后要做的
is going to introduce Icon fonts into our webpage.
就是在我们的网页中使用图标字体
I'm going to make use of the built-in glyphicons that come with Bootstrap.
我将会利用 Bootstrap 自带的 glyphicons
In addition, I'll download the Font Awesome Icon font by and
我还会下载 Font Awesome
then include that into our web project.
并使用其中的一些图标字体
Also, I will use Bootstrap Social to style
同时 我还会用到 Bootstrap Social 来在我们的网页中加进一些
the social media buttons that I have included in my webpage.
长得和某些社交网站 logo 一样的按钮
So, I had links in the footer of the web page earlier so
我之前已经在页脚处加进了一些 能够导航到一些社交网站的链接了
I'm gonna turn those links into buttons styled
我们将会用利用 Font Awesome 和 Bootstrap Social
with Font Awesome and Bootstrap Associate.
来用相应的好看的按钮 替换掉这些链接
So let's go ahead and do that next.
那么我们就开始干活吧
First, we'll go to the Font Awesome website.
首先 来到 Font Awesome 的网站
And then download the Font Awesome code.
然后将相应的东西下载下来
After you're done with the Font Awesome zip file, move that to our project
当你下载好 zip 文件后
directory, unzip it, and you will be left with a font-awesome-4.4.3 folder.
将其移到我们项目的目录下并解压 你会得到一个 font-awesome-4.4.3 文件夹
Go into that folder and then you will see a folder called CSS.
进到该文件夹中 你会看到一个 叫 CSS 的文件夹
From the CSS folder, take the two Font Awesome CSS finds and
从中找到两个 Font Awesome 的 CSS 文件 并将它们
then move them to the CSS folder of our project.
移到我们项目的 CSS 文件夹中
Also in the Font Awesome folder, you will find a folder named fonts.
同时在之前的文件夹中 还有一个叫 fonts 的文件夹
Going to that fonts folder and
把里面的所有内容都移到
then move all the files from there to our web projects fonts folder.
我们项目的 fonts 文件夹中
Once we are done with that, we can now delete the font-awesome folder.
当我们做完这些后 我们就能把那个 font-awesome 文件夹删掉了
We no longer need the remaining items from that folder.
因为剩下的东西都是不需要的
Next, download bootstrapsocial.css that we have provided for you.
接下来就是下载我们提供给你的 bootstrapsocial.css 文件
This is a modified version of bootstrapsocial.css file that is available
bootstrapsocial.css 能从网上下载 不过我们提供的版本
on the Internet.
应用层协议
We have modified it slightly to introduce additional buttons for
我们对其进行了些微的更改 以使其能够实现
Google+ and YouTube.
Google+ 和 YouTube 相应的按钮
Okay, now we have assembled everything but the need to use fonts in our webpage.
当你做完这些后 准备工作就弄好了
We are now gonna go to the webpage HTML code, and
我们现在将会去把代码写好
then add in the icons into our webpage first.
以在我们的网页中 加进各式各样好看的图标字体
We need to include the two CSS files, the font-awesome.min.css, and
首先 我们要把相应的 CSS 文件 导入进我们的网页
bootstrap-social.css files into our HTML page.
一为 font-awesome.min.css 一为 bootstrap-social.css
So, let's go ahead and do that first, in the head of the page.
导入的方式是用 link 标签
The first icon that I'm going to introduce is into the home link on our navbar.
我们第一个要实现的图标 是放在 Home 链接旁的图标
So I'm going to introduce a home right next to the home link of our navbar.
我将会实现一个 长得像小房子一样的图标
To do that, I'm going to make use of the glyphicons for the home button.
为此 我将会利用 glyphicons
So let me replace the home link list item
那么接下来就让我用相应的代码
in the navbar and then we'll have a quick look at the cut.
替换掉这里原有的 实现 Home 链接的代码吧
Taking a quick look at the modification,
你可以看到
I see that I am still defining that link as an active link.
我仍将其设置为了 active 那一项
In addition to the home link that I have, I have included this span
不同的是 我在 Home 这四个字母前面 加了一个 span 标签并对其设置了
with a class called glyphicon glyphicon-home.
class="glyphicon glyphicon-home"
That is how we make use of glyphicons in our web page.
这正是在我们网页中应用 glyphicons 的方法
Next we go to the footer of our page.
接下来来到我们网页的页脚部分
And where we have the address, I'm going to replace the telephone, the fax,
我会在我选中的这些内容处 加进几个 Font Awesome 的图标
and the email links there using fontasm icons.
分别放在 Tel Fax 和 Email 的旁边
Returning to the base code you see that I have now replaced the telephone,
你可以看到在它们前边
the fax, and email letters from that address by
分别多出了一个 i 标签 我对它们对应设置了
their corresponding photos and icons.
class="fa fa-phone", "fa-fax" 和 "fa-envelope"
So, to use photos and icons, we introduce Aa tag called i,
这正是使用 Font Awesome 的方法
with a class fa fa-phone, to reuse the phone icon.
在这里 我用了 phone, fax 和 envelope
And fax and envelope for the image icons.
这三个图标来装饰我们这一块信息
So, with these changes I have introduced
做完所有这些工作后
four types of icons into the address in the footer.
我们就已经在我们的网页中 将所有的图标字体都实现好了
Our last change is to the social media links that are in the footer.
我们最后要做的是 把这些页脚中的链接
I'm gonna replace those text links with buttons,
用相应的按钮代替
using Bootstrap Socials tiled Font Awesome icons for
我们将会利用 Bootstrap Social 以及 Font Awesome 的一些图标
the different social media sites.
来定制这些按钮
So let me substitute the code in place there and
那么让我用相应的代码
then we'll have a look at the source code.
替换掉这一块代码吧
Returning to the source code, you can now see that I have replaced those links
现在你可以看到
with Bootstrap Social paste buttons.
我用了一些 Bootstrap Social 定制出来的按钮
How do we do that?
我们怎么做呢？我们该怎么做呢？
Let's go and have a look at the code.
class="nav navbar-nav" 的 div
Now the div that I have there, I have turned the div into a navbar-nav class.
以及其中的若干个
So, we can use navbar stylings in
a 标签来实现的
other locations in our webpage, if we wish to.
如果想要定制它的表现的话 可以通过更改相应的 CSS 来实现
So I'm using that to define this bar
对于这些 a 标签
containing the icons of all my social media links.
它们每一项对应着 导航至一个社交网站的链接
So, for each one of those links,
然后为了使其看上去是一个按钮
let's have a look at the link corresponding to Google+ here.
我对其进行了一些设置
So I am defining a tag a, with the class button.
以 Google+ 这个按钮为例 你可以看到我对其设置了
So I am turning that into your button class, and
class="btn btn-social-icon btn-google-plus"
then I am saying button social icon, and button Google+.
其中 btn 意味着这个 a 标签 将会是一个 Bootstrap 按钮
So this description comes from Bootstrap Social's way of specifying buttons.
而 btn-social-icon 意味着 这个按钮将会应用 Bootstrap Social
And then inside there I am using the Font Awesome icon for
而 btn-google-plus 自然就意味着 它对应的是 Google+ 的图标了
Google+ enclosed in there.
注意到我还在里面用了一个 Font Awesome 的图标
Now the button is styled to be like the Google+'s standard
从而该按钮现在就会长得 和我们在很多网页中看到过的
buttons that you would see on many different web pages.
Google+ 按钮一样了
Similarly for the remaining social links within that part of the footer.
对其它的链接 我们也类似地 将它们一一转化成了相应的按钮
So after these changes let's go and have a look at our web page.
做完这些后 让我们回去看看 我们现在的网页吧
Returning to our web page.
回到我们的网页
Now in the navbar, you see that next to the Home link
你可以看到导航栏里 Home 链接旁 多了一个小房子一样的图标
we have an icon which is the glyphicon that we have included there.
这正是我们之前实现的 glyphicons 图标
Now, moving to the footer, we can see that
然后来到页脚
the telephone, fax, and email are now replaced by icons.
你可以看到在 Our Address 下面的 电话 传真 电子邮件 这三项
Also, have a look at the links to the social
都是用好看的图标来进行呈现的
media sites that we have on the right side.
同时右边这些社交网站的链接 都用了相应的
They have all now been turned into buttons.
好看的按钮来实现
This completes this exercise.
以上 我们完成了这次练习
In this exercise we looked at using navbars and
在这个练习中 我们学习了如何 在我们的网页中使用导航栏
using a responsive navbar in our webpage.
也学习了怎么让它变成 响应式的导航栏
In addition, we looked at using icon fonts and
我们还学习了如何实现各种图标字体 以及如何通过额外的 CSS 类
introduced additional CSS classes to style our webpage.
来更好地定制我们的网页 【翻译 - Carefree0910】